I'm an award-winning Visual Designer with over 7 years of in-house experience in building brands, telling stories and solving problems. I'm recognized as adaptable, resourceful and proactive, a clear communicator, and a leader with effective relationship building skills. My work is rooted in empathy and big-picture thinking. My mission: make awesome things and get stuff done.

# Work Experience

#### Visual Designer . 2015-Present

Self-Employed: Various CPG, Wine & Agency Clients · Oakland & Sonoma County, CA

- Design & production of websites, social media graphics, editorial layout, advertising, packaging, illustrations, logos and more.
- · Photograph, source, and retouch lifestyle & product photography.
- Concept and iterate designs based upon feedback, user research and testing.

### Graphic Designer . 2018-2020

Fetzer Vineyards · Healdsburg, CA

- Took creative lead on the award-winning annual report, Mapping the Road. Led style, layout, photo treatments, naming, and copy-editing. Resulted in raising B Corporation score by 15 points. Deliverables included a 36 page report with die-cut cover, Times Square billboard, PR mailer and microsite.
- Web & social media graphics, front end microsite design.
- · Layout and design of retail point of sale, advertising, marketing materials, and PR mailers.

### Graphic Designer . 2018

Dry Creek Vineyards · Healdsburg, CA

- Lead creation of new brand positioning through retail POS.
- Managed vendors, production and publishing of all materials.

### Graphic Designer / Production Coordinator . 2013-2015

National Geographic Society, Book Publishing · Washington, D.C.

- Combined ten sales catalogs, with various stakeholders and objectives, into two catalogs a year. Responsible for entire process from concept to finished materials. Resulted in 40%+ cost-savings for all sales departments.
- Initiated revised work flow processes, including establishment of project tracking database and Digital Asset Management system, resulting in 50% efficiency improvement.
- Coordinated creation of over 20 simultaneous projects with internal mid-size team, printers, freelancers, and videographers under tight deadlines, in an agile setting.
- Designed promotional marketing materials, social media & web graphics, event and trade show signage, and microsites.

## Account Manager / Graphic Designer . 2007-2013

National Geographic Society, International Brand Licensing · Washington, D.C.

- Managed 30+ international accounts by licensing brand and book publishing rights.
- · Negotiated contracts and finalized high value sales and annual minimum guarantees.
- Participated in sales presentations, and represented the team at international book fairs.
- Designed catalogs, from concept to print, coordinating with all stakeholders & vendors.
- · Designed sell sheets, event signage and booth layouts.

#### Soft Skills

Critical & strategic thinking
Concepting & iteration
Project management
Transforming complex topics
Working under pressure with
shifting deadlines & priorities

#### **Toolkit**

Adobe CC (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, XD, Premiere, After Effects), Sketch, Figma, Asana, Trello, Dropbox, Google Drive, Miro, Slack, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap

### Awards & Recognition

Mapping the Road – Fetzer Vineyards, 2019 Annual Report: Graphic Design USA 2019 Award Wine Pack Design Awards 2020

AIGA Portfolio Review — Seasoned Pro, July 2020. One of 12 selected for a live national review.

#### Education

UC Berkeley Extension, Oct. 2020 Certificate: UX/UI/FE Bootcamp

Santa Rosa Junior College Certificate: Advanced HTML & CSS

Ball State University, Muncie, IN, BFA • Graphic Design • Photography

## Volunteering

Secretary @ Letter People Sonoma

# Selected Projects

- Mapping the Road | Award Winner | Annual Report, Web, OOH | Design Lead | Fetzer Vineyards | Corporate Consciousness Report
- go.carium.com | Jr Web Designer | Flight Design Agency | Produced images and graphics
- VoteReady | UC Berkeley | UX/UI App Case Study | UX Researcher, Design Lead | Designed a mobile app to engage and empower
  voters, creating features unseen amongst competition.
- Bike East Bay | Website Redesign Case Study | UC Berkeley | UX Researcher, Design Lead, Project Manager | Redesign of existing website, updates based upon research and testing. Simplified site and made more engaging.